

■ DruSerkes@gmail.com

druserkes

**** 203-912-2047

♀ New York, NY

in dru-serkes

O druserkes

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer with a passion for crafting creative solutions. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes both one-on-one and in group settings. Loyal team player with a self-starter attitude.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jasmine, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: Git, PostgreSQL, Axios, Jinja, VSCode, Heroku, Netlify

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration, Attention to detail, Initiative, Time Management, Handling Pressure

PROJECTS

LYRIFY 2020

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- Crafted responsive single-page app with React and Material UI components
 - Built out backend with Node.js/Express
 - Follow Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify
 - Consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation
 - · Provide front end state with Redux
 - Administer client side routing with React Router
 - Validate and clean user inputs for custom search

THE EASY MEAL 2020

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- Built a Flask Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates
- Secured against CSRF with form validation
- Applied bcrypt authentication for user login
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes
- · Cached recipe data with PostgreSQL
- Implemented site-wide search capability with JavaScript (Axios, jQuery)
- Responsively styled UI with Bootstrap and custom CSS

JOBLY 2020

Mock job-seeking website

- Developed RESTful API with Node/Express
- Built clean UI with React
- Implemented form validation with Formik and JSONSchema
- Managed data with PostgreSQL
- Handle user authentication/authorization with JWT

HACK OR SNOOZE 2020

Hacker News clone

- Developed OOP methods for consuming an external API
- · Add UI event handling logic with jQuery
- Learned and refactored an existing codebase
- Defended decisions and made adjustments during a live code-review

EXPERIENCE

SPRINGBOARD, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CAREER TRACK

Student

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material
- 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
- Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects
- · Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

JERSEY BOYS

Actor

New York, NY Aug. 2015 to Current

Apr. 2020 to Current

- Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show
- Understudied and carried out the duties of 6 different roles, going on as late as mid-show
- Single-handedly saved 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

KING SCHOOL

Acting Coach

Stamford, CT Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020

- Advised on best practices for pursuing professional careers in entertainment
- Offered young professionals methods for approaching new material
- Engaged with students of all experience levels one-on-one, producing greater understanding and depth of performance

EDUCATION

Springboard

2020

Software Engineering Career Track Certification

Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient